<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../entries2html.xsl" ?>
<entry name="dialog" namespace="fn" type="Widget" widgetnamespace="mobile">
	<desc>Opens content in an interactive overlay.</desc>
	<longdesc>
		<p>Any page can be presented as a modal dialog by adding the <code>data-rel="dialog"</code> attribute to the page anchor link. When the "dialog" attribute is applied, the framework adds styles to add rounded corners, margins around the page and a dark background to make the "dialog" appear to be suspended above the page.</p>
<pre><code>
&lt;a href="foo.html" data-rel="dialog"&gt;Open dialog&lt;/a&gt;

</code></pre>
<a href="http://jquerymobile.com/demos/1.1.0/docs/pages/dialog.html" data-role="button">Open Dialog</a>
<h3>Transitions</h3>

<p>By default, the dialog will open with a 'pop' transition. Like all pages, you can specify any page transition you want on the dialog by adding the <code>data-transition</code> attribute to the link. To make it feel more dialog-like, we recommend specifying a transition of "pop", "slideup" or "flip".</p>
<pre><code>
&lt;a href="foo.html" data-rel="dialog" data-transition="pop"&gt;Open dialog&lt;/a&gt;

</code></pre>
<h3>Closing dialogs</h3>

<p>When any link is clicked within in a dialog, the framework will automatically close the dialog and transition to the requested page, just as if the dialog were a normal page. To create a "cancel" button in a dialog, just link to the page that triggered the dialog to open and add the <code>data-rel="back"</code> attribute to your link. This pattern of linking to the previous page is also usable in non-JS devices as well.
</p><p>
For JavaScript-generated links, you can simply set the href attribute to "#" and use the <code>data-rel="back"</code> attribute. You can also call the dialog's <code>close()</code> method to programmatically close dialogs, for example: <code>$('.ui-dialog').dialog('close'). </code></p>

<h4>Setting the close button text</h4>

<p>Just like the page plugin, you can set a dialog's close button text through an option or data attribute. The option can be configured for all dialogs by binding to the <code>mobileinit</code> event and setting the <code>$.mobile.dialog.prototype.options.closeBtnText</code> property to a string of your choosing, or you can place the data attribute <code>data-close-btn-text</code> to configure the text from your markup.</p>

<h3>History &amp; Back button behavior</h3>

<p>Since dialogs are typically used to support actions within a page, the framework does not include dialogs in the hash state history tracking. This means that dialogs will not appear in your browsing history chronology when the Back button is clicked. For example, if you are on a page, click a link to open a dialog, close the dialog, then navigate to another page, if you were to click the browser's Back button at that point you will navigate back to the first page, not the dialog.</p>

<h3>Styling &amp; theming</h3>
<p>Dialogs can be styled with different theme swatches, just like any page by adding <code>data-theme</code> attributes to the header, content, or footer containers.</p>
<p>Dialogs appear to be floating above an overlay layer. This overlay adopts the swatch 'a' content color by default, but the <code>data-overlay-theme</code> attribute can be added to the page wrapper to set the overlay to any swatch letter. </p>
<p>Dialogs can also be used more like a control sheet to offer multiple buttons if you simply remove the top margin from the dialog's inner container element. For example, if your dialog page had a class of <code>my-dialog</code>, you could add this CSS to pin that dialog to the top: <code>.ui-dialog.my-dialog .ui-dialog-contain { margin-top: 0 }</code>, or you could just apply that style to all dialogs with <code>.ui-dialog .ui-dialog-contain { margin-top: 0 }</code>.</p>
<h3>Dialog width and margins</h3>
<p>
For the sake of readability, dialogs have a default <code>max-width</code> of 500 pixels (plus 15px padding on each side). There is also a 10% top <code>margin</code> to give dialogs larger top margin on larger screens, but collapse to a small margin on smartphones. To override these styles, add the following CSS override rule to your stylesheet and tweak as needed:
<pre><code>
.ui-dialog .ui-header,
.ui-dialog .ui-content,
.ui-dialog .ui-footer {
	max-width: 500px;
	margin: 10% auto 15px auto;
}
</code></pre>
</p>
	</longdesc>
	<created>1.0</created>
	<options>
	  <option name="data-transition" default='"pop"'>
	    <desc>Opens the dialog using the specified transition. (Note the recommended transitions for a more realistic dialog effect appear in bold).
	    <p>Possible values: fade, <b>pop</b>, <b>flip</b>, turn, flow, slidefade, slide, slideup, <b>slidedown</b>, none. </p>
	    </desc>
	    <type name="String" />
	  </option>
	  <option name="closeBtnText" default='"Close"'>
	    <desc>Customizes the text of the close button which is helpful for translating this into different languages. This is displayed as an icon-only button by default so the text isn't visible on-screen, but is read by screen readers so this is an important accessibility feature.
			<p>This option is also exposed as a data attribute: <code>data-close-btn-text</code>.</p>
        </desc>
        <type name="String" />
	  </option>
	  <option name="initSelector"  default='":jqmData(role=&#39;dialog&#39;)"'>
		<desc>This is used to define the selectors (element types, data roles, etc.) that will automatically be initialized as dialogs. To change which elements are initialized, bind this option to the mobileinit event:
<pre><code>
$( document ).bind( "mobileinit", function(){
    $.mobile.dialog.prototype.options.initSelector = ".mydialog";
});</code></pre>
		</desc>
		<type name="CSS selector string" />
	  </option>
	</options>
	<events>
	<event name="create">
	<desc>Triggered when a dialog is created</desc>
	<pre><code>$( ".selector" ).dialog({
   create: function(event, ui) { ... }
});
</code></pre>
	</event>
	</events>
	<methods>
	  <method name="close">
	    <desc>Closes the dialog.</desc>
	  </method>
	</methods>
	<theming>
	  <theme name="data-theme (as a data-attribute)">
	    <desc>Dialogs can be styled with different theme swatches, just like any page by adding <code>data-theme</code> attributes to the header, content, or footer containers. <p>Possible values: swatch letter (a-z)</p></desc>
	    <type name="String" />
	  </theme>
	 <theme name="overlayTheme" default='"a"'>
	   <desc>Dialogs appear to be floating above an overlay layer. This overlay adopts the swatch A content color by default, but the data-overlay-theme attribute can be added to the page wrapper to set the overlay to any swatch letter.<p> Possible values: swatch letter (a-z)</p>
	   <p>This option is also exposed as a data attribute: <code>data-overlay-theme</code>.</p>
	   </desc>
	   <type name="String" />
	 </theme>
	</theming>
	<example>
		<desc>A basic example of opening a page as a dialog by adding <code>data-rel="dialog"</code> to the anchor tag.</desc>
		<code><![CDATA[]]></code>
		<html><![CDATA[  <div data-role="header">
        <h2>Dialog Example 1</h2>
      </div>
      <div data-role="content">
        <a href="#dialogPage" data-rel="dialog">Open dialog</a>
      </div>
      <div data-role="footer">
        <h2></h2>
      </div>
    </div>
    <div data-role="page" id="dialogPage">
      <div data-role="header">
        <h2>Dialog</h2>
      </div>
      <div data-role="content">
        <p>I am a dialog</p>
      </div>]]></html>
	</example>
	<category slug="widgets"/>
</entry>
