<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry name="orientationchange" type="event" return="jQuery">
	<title>orientationchange</title>
	<desc>Device portrait/landscape orientation event</desc>
	<longdesc>
		<p>The jQuery Mobile <code>orientationchange</code> event triggers when a device orientation changes, either by turning the device vertically or horizontally. When bound to this event the callback function has the event object. The event object contains an <code>orientation</code> property equal to either "portrait" or "landscape".</p>
		<p>Note, we bind to the browser's resize event when <code>orientationchange</code> is not natively supported or if <code>$.mobile.orientationChangeEnabled</code> is set to false.</p>
		
		<div style="padding: 0.4em 15px; background: #FFF3A5; ">
		<h3>orientationchange timing</h3>

		<p>The timing of the <code>orientationchange</code> with relation to the change of the client height and width is different between browsers, though the current implementation will give you the correct value for <code>event.orientation</code> derived from <code>window.orientation</code>. This means that if your bindings are dependent on the height and width values you may want to disable <code>orientationChange</code> altogether with <code>$.mobile.orientationChangeEnabled = false</code> to let the fallback resize code trigger your bindings.</p></div>
		<p></p>
		<xi:include href="../includes/core-extension-desc.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<pre>
		<code><![CDATA[
			$(function(){
				/* 
				  Bind an event to window.orientationchange that, when the device is turned, 
				  gets the orientation and displays it to on screen.
				 */
				$(window).bind( 'orientationchange', orientationChangeHandler );

				function orientationChangeHandler( event ) {
					$('h1#orientation').html( 'This device is in ' + event.orientation + ' mode!' );
				}
				// You can also manually force this event to fire.
				$(window).orientationchange();
			}); 
		]]></code>
	</pre>
	<p>Visit this from your orientation-enabled device to see it in action!
		<iframe id="orientationIframe" src="/resources/orientationchange/example1.html" style="width:100%;height:90px;border:0px"></iframe>
	</p>
	</longdesc>
	<added>1.0</added>
	<signature>
		<argument name="callback" type="Function" optional="true">
			<desc>A function to invoke after the the orientationchange event fires.</desc>
		</argument>
	</signature>
	<category slug="events"/>
</entry>
