<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../entries2html.xsl" ?>
<entry name="page" namespace="fn" type="widget" widgetnamespace="mobile" event-prefix="page" init-selector=":jqmData(role=&#39;page&#39;)">
	<title>Page Widget</title>
	<desc>Primary unit of content.</desc>
	<longdesc>
		<p>The page widget is responsible for managing a single item in jQuery Mobile's page-based architecture. It is designed to support either single page widgets within a HTML document, or multiple local internal linked page widgets within a HTML document.</p>

		<p>The goal of this model is to allow developers to create websites using best practices &#8212; where ordinary links will "just work" without any special configuration &#8212; while creating a rich, native-like experience that can't be achieved with standard HTTP requests.</p>

		<p><strong>Caveat:</strong> Documents containing multiple pages cause Internet Explorer 7 to exhibit incorrect behavior when its "Back" button is pressed. In particular, if the user navigates between several of the pages internal to the document that has been loaded and then clicks the "Back" button to return to the start page, there will be occasions when clicking the "Back" button does not cause a return to the previous page. However, clicking the "Back" button enough times will eventually return the user through the performed navigation sequence back to the start page.</p>
		<p>Thus, if Internet Explorer 7 represents a significant proportion of the targeted user base, we recommended that pages be organized as individual HTML documents containing single page widgets, rather than as a single HTML document containing multiple internal pages.</p>
	</longdesc>
	<added>1.0</added>
	<options>
		<option name="domCache" default="false" example-value="true">
			<desc>
				<p>Sets whether to keep the page in the DOM after the user has navigated away from it.</p>
				<p>This option is also exposed as a data attribute: <code>data-dom-cache="true"</code>.</p>
			</desc>
			<type name="Boolean" />
		</option>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-option-initSelector.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<option name="keepNativeDefault" default=":jqmData(role='none'), :jqmData(role='nojs')" example-value='".do-not-enhance"'>
			<desc>
				<p>The value of this option is a selector that will be used to prevent elements matching it from being enhanced.</p>
				<p>This option is also exposed as a data attribute: <code>data-keep-native-default=".do-not-enhance"</code>.</p>
			</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="theme" default='"a"' example-value='"b"'>
			<desc>
				Sets the color scheme (swatch) for the <placeholder name="name" /> widget. It accepts a single letter from a-z that maps to the swatches included in your theme.
				<p>Possible values: swatch letter (a-z).</p>
				<p>This option is also exposed as a data attribute: <code>data-theme="b"</code>.</p>
			</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
	</options>
	<events>
		<event name="beforecreate">
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
			</argument>
			<desc><p>Triggered before a page is created. If one of the handlers returns false, the page is not created.</p>
			</desc>
		</event>
		<event name="create">
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
			</argument>
			<desc><p>Triggered after a page has been created. jQuery Mobile will use this event to apply its enhancements to the page.</p>
			</desc>
		</event>
	</events>
	<methods>
		<method name="keepNativeSelector">
			<desc>Returns the selector used to filter elements which are not to be enhanced.</desc>
		</method>
		<method name="removeContainerBackground">
			<desc>Removes the background swatch from the page widget's container (usually the body).</desc>
		</method>
		<method name="setContainerBackground" example-params='"c"'>
			<desc>Sets a new background swatch for the page widget's container (usually the body).</desc>
			<argument name="theme" type="String">
			</argument>
		</method>
	</methods>
	<example>
		<desc>A basic example of a page.</desc>
		<html><![CDATA[
<div data-role="page" id="page1">
	<div data-role="header">
		<h1>Page header (optional): Example page</h1>
	</div>
	<div data-role="content">
		<h2>Page content</h2>
		<p>Page content goes here.</p>
	</div>
	<div data-role="footer">
		<h1>Page footer (optional)</h1>
	</div>
</div>
]]></html>
	</example>
	<category slug="widgets"/>
</entry>
